<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<page pageId="Page5" pageName="Planets" title="">
    <abstract></abstract>
    <keywords></keywords>
    <contents>
        <line Align="Left">
            <content style="Normal">A planet can be owned by one of the 4 teams.  In rare cases, a failed attempt to capture a planet may result in that planet having 0 armies and being “independent”.  Independent planets appear gray.  A planet that has not been visited by your team since the start of the game, or since the last time it was captured, will also appear gray.</content>
        </line>
        <line Align="Left">
            <image height="92.0" style="Normal" leftMargin="0.0" bottomMargin="0.0" rightMargin="0.0" width="83.0" topMargin="0.0" imageId="unknown-or-indi-planet.png"></image>
        </line>
        <line Align="Left">
            <content style="Normal">A planet with extra repair facilities will show a wrench icon in the center.  A planet with extra fuel will show a fuel can on the right side.  Orbiting a friendly planet with these facilities will result in faster repair or refueling.</content>
        </line>
        <line Align="Left">
            <image height="87.0" style="Normal" leftMargin="0.0" bottomMargin="0.0" rightMargin="0.0" width="74.0" topMargin="0.0" imageId="fuel-repair-planet.png"></image>
        </line>
        <line Align="Left">
            <content style="Normal">A planet may not have any special facilities:</content>
        </line>
        <line Align="Left">
            <image height="108.0" style="Normal" leftMargin="0.0" bottomMargin="0.0" rightMargin="0.0" width="95.0" topMargin="0.0" imageId="empty-planet.png"></image>
        </line>
        <line Align="Left">
            <content style="Normal">You can use the l (lowercase L) command to “lock on” to a planet and, when you get there, orbit it.  A planet with more than 4 armies will also show the army icon on its left side.  When you orbit a friendly or enemy planet, you can bomb it (b), beam up armies (z) or beam down armies (x).  Bombing is only effective when there are more than 4 enemy armies.  The last few enemy armies have to be destroyed by beaming down armies.  Bombing, followed by 5 armies, is generally sufficient to capture any enemy planet.</content>
        </line>
        <line Align="Left">
            <image height="118.0" style="Normal" leftMargin="0.0" bottomMargin="0.0" rightMargin="0.0" width="93.0" topMargin="0.0" imageId="orbiting-planet-with-armies.png"></image>
        </line>
        <line Align="Left">
            <content style="Normal">Enemy planets damage your ship if you are close to it.</content>
        </line>
        <line Align="Left">
            <content style="Normal"></content>
        </line>
        <line Align="Left">
            <content style="Normal"></content>
        </line>
    </contents>
</page>