<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<page pageId="Page4" pageName="Ships" title="">
    <abstract></abstract>
    <keywords></keywords>
    <contents>
        <line Align="Left">
            <content style="Heading2">Cruisers</content>
        </line>
        <line Align="Left">
            <content style="Normal">Cruisers are standard ships and are well rounded for movement and combat.  They have 100 shields, 100 hull, 40-point torpedoes, 100-point (max) lasers, 10,000 fuel, and can go speed 9.  Beginner players should play cruisers.  Their designation is CA.</content>
        </line>
        <line Align="Left">
            <content style="Heading2">Battleships</content>
        </line>
        <line Align="Left">
            <content style="Normal">Battleships have upgraded shields (130) and hull (130).  Their weapons are only marginally better (40 point torpedoes, 105-point (max) lasers.  They are slower (speed 8).  While they have larger fuel reserves (14,000) they use fuel quickly in combat and are most effective in the vicinity of a fuel planet  Their designation is BB.</content>
        </line>
        <line Align="Left">
            <content style="Heading2">Destroyers</content>
        </line>
        <line Align="Left">
            <content style="Normal">Destroyers are faster than cruisers (speed 10) but are more fragile (85 shield, 85 hull).  Their torpedoes only do 30 points of damage and their lasers max out at 85 damage.  Some servers require a rank of Lieutenant before allowing someone to play a destroyer.</content>
        </line>
        <line Align="Left">
            <content style="Heading2">Scout</content>
        </line>
        <line Align="Left">
            <content style="Normal">Scouts are very fast (speed 12) but are very fragile (75 shield, 75 hull).  Scouts have very weak weapons (25 point torpedoes, 75 max on lasers).  Scouts can only carry a max of 2 armies.  Scouts only have 5000 fuel.  One or two scouts are best used to bomb enemy rear planets and entice multiple enemy players into a futile chase.  ) is speed 10.  ! is speed 11.  @ is speed 12.  % is maximum speed.</content>
        </line>
        <line Align="Left">
            <content style="Heading2">Assault Ship</content>
        </line>
        <line Align="Left">
            <content style="Normal">Assault ships are designed to capture heavily defended enemy planets.  They have 200 hull but only 80 shields.  This is designed to deal with the fact that shields have to be down to beam down armies.  They have very effective bombing systems.  They have 30 point torpedoes and 80 point max lasers.  Their max speed is 8 and they have 6000 fuel.</content>
        </line>
        <line Align="Left">
            <content style="Heading2">Starbase</content>
        </line>
        <line Align="Left">
            <content style="Normal">A staircase is a special ship, usually requiring the rank of commander to play.  It only moves at speed 2.  It has 600 hull, 500 shields, 60000 fuel.  Its torpedoes only do 30 points damage, but its lasers are very powerful (120 point max) and fire at twice the normal rate.  Friendly ships can lock onto a starbase, dock, and beam armies up or down.  It usually takes several enemy ships working as a team to destroy a starbase.  A team can only have one starbase at a time.  When a starbase is destroyed your team cannot launch a new one for 30 minutes.</content>
        </line>
        <line Align="Left">
            <content style="Heading2">Battlecruiser</content>
        </line>
        <line Align="Left">
            <content style="Normal">Some Netrek variants (Sturgeon) have other ship types.  Most notably the battlecruiser (designate GA).  On this client they appear as cruisers on the tactical map.</content>
        </line>
        <line Align="Left">
            <content style="Normal"></content>
        </line>
    </contents>
</page>